Mikayla Zwerdling - New York, NY zwerdlingmikayla@gmail.com

Portfolio - mikaylazwerdling.com linkedin.com/in/mikayla-zwerdling/ 864-631-7180

Studying Graphic Design at Parsons School of Design at the New School

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY:

I am currently studying graphic design at the Parsons School of Design at The New School in New York City (Finishing Sophomore year). I have over 5 years of intense experience and educational instruction in visual arts and graphic design, gained while attending the Governor's School for the Arts and Humanities residential High School, Maryland Institute College of Art "MICA" (pre-college) Program and The Fine Arts Center. In addition, I have over 5 years of work experience in graphic design, creating and editing corporate PowerPoint presentations, banner ads, logo design, whitepapers, eBooks and video production. I also received a National Silver Medal in Design from Scholastic Art and Writing.

I have extensive expertise in Typographic Design, Advertising and Branding, Experimental Print Design, 2D Animation, Adobe Suite (Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, Premiere Pro, Lightroom, After Effects), Kinetic Typography, Logo Design, HTML, Corporate PowerPoint Presentation Development and Video Production. Here is a link to my portfolio http://mikaylazwerdling.com

Graphic Design Expertise

- Typography
- Adobe Suite (Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, Premiere Pro, Lightroom, After Effects)
- Advertising and Branding
- Print/Book Design
- Experimental Typography

- Web Design
- HTML and CSS
- Kinetic Typography
- Logo Design
- Corporate PowerPoint Presentation Development
- Video Production

Technical/Software Proficiencies

Adobe Suite (Illustrator, Photoshop, InDesign, Premiere Pro, Lightroom, After Effects), Figma, Sketch, HTML and CSS, DragonFrame, PowerPoint, MS Word, Excel, Google Docs

EDUCATION:

Parsons School of Design at the New School - New York, NY 8/2018 - Present (Class of 2022)

A private art and design college located in the Greenwich Village neighborhood of Lower Manhattan.

Coursework: Major - Graphic Design

- Web Design and Development
- Interaction Design
- Fashion Editorial Design
- Narrative Film and Editing
- Drawing/Imaging
- Space/Materiality

- Creative Coding (html, css, javascript)
- Advanced Typography
- Sustainability and Design
- Typographic History
- Intro to Japanese

<u>The South Carolina Governor's School for the Arts & Humanities</u> - Greenville, SC 8/2016 - 5/2018 - GPA (4.5)

Nationally recognized, pre-professional residential arts and academic high school. Students live on campus in a safe and structured environment which allows them to truly become immersed in their art discipline and their studies. Students gain experience preparing portfolios, exhibiting artwork in regional exhibitions, and entering local and national competitions.

Governor's School Coursework:

Graphic Design

- Logo Design
- Branding
- Experimental Typography
- Font Design
- Poster Design
- Advertising

2D Design/Drawing

- Printmaking
- Painting
- Life Drawing

Animation

- Motion Graphics
- Stop Motion
- Kinetic Typography
- Hand Drawn

3D Design

- Functional Ceramics
- Metalworking
- Architecture
- Sculpture

<u>Maryland Institute College of Art</u> "MICA" (Pre-college) Program, Baltimore, MD Summer 2017

Acknowledged nationally as a premier leader in art and design education, MICA is deliberately cultivating a new generation of artists.

• Studied Animation and Graphic Design in Summer 2017 Intensive Program

<u>Fine Arts Center</u> - Greenville, SC 8/2014 - 5/2016

The Fine Arts Center was established in 1974 as the first specialized arts school in the State of South Carolina to provide advanced comprehensive arts instruction to students who are artistically talented and wish to take an intensive pre-professional program of study.

Coursework:

- Painting/Drawing
- Ceramics
- Darkroom photography
- Metalworking/Jewelry

CAREER EXPERIENCE:

Frankie CoLab

Associate Sales Stylist, Hudson Yards - NY, NY 7/2019 - 3/2020

Frankie CoLab is a designer store featuring highly limited designer editions, rare-find independent brands, avant-garde labels and exclusive artist and designer products.

- Designed store signage
- Created and implemented employee charts
- Sales and marketing activities such as event planning, social media, etc.
- Maintain outstanding product knowledge.
- Process all POS transactions accurately and swiftly.
- Provide and instill an exceptional sense of standards and culture of professionalism.
- Complete daily stock requirement.
- Maintain an organized selling floor and stock rooms along with floor asset protection.
- Receiving, checking, and ticketing in-coming inventory and shipments.

AG Jeans New York, NY
Retail Sales Associate for AG Jeans Hudson Yards
3/2019 - 7/2019

AG Jeans (Adriano Goldschmied) is an exclusively premium, socially active, and responsible denim brand. Creates, manages, and develops customer relations using knowledge of the brand, strong sales strategies and high levels of customer service.

- Establish and maintain a solid understanding of the company Point of Sale System in order to efficiently process customer and store transactions.
- Maintain a clean and well merchandised store environment that meets company standards.
- Protects company assets by following all loss prevention procedures.
- Maintains a high level of PK (product knowledge) by staying current with supplied product knowledge tools and seasonal look books.
- Consistently exceeded monthly Individual Sales Plans.

<u>Parsons School of Design - Open Campus</u> - New York, NY Pre-College Teaching Assistant 9/2018 - 12/2018

- Instructor of Adobe Illustrator and Photoshop to New York City High School Students.
- Taught basic type design and photo manipulation, contributed to critiques, gave ideas and helped expand student concepts.

<u>Global Expansion, Inc.</u> Greenville, SC

Freelance Graphic Designer for Global Staffing, Human Resources and Career Coaching Company 7/2018 - Present

- Created and managed visual media print and web.
- Logo design, website banner ads, business cards.
- Designed and managed PowerPoint marketing presentations for company services.
- Layout and design of Whitepapers and eBooks.

<u>Foreign Staffing, Inc.</u> Greenville, SC

1/2014 - 12/2016

Freelance Graphic Designer for International Staffing and Payroll Company

- Created and managed visual media print and web.
- Directed and produced 12 educational videos for company's website and You Tube channel.
- Designed and managed PowerPoint marketing services presentations, whitepapers, eBooks & banner ads.

MISCELLANEOUS:

- Member of Girl Scouts 2006 2018
- South Carolina Governor's School for the Arts & Humanities
 Film Club September 2016 May 2018
 Created and Distributed Promotional Materials for Club screenings
- Yearbook Staff September 2017 May 2018
 Developed page spread layouts for school wide yearbook
- City of Greenville March For Our Lives Against Gun Violence Designed Event Poster
- Scholastic Art & Writing Awards, the nation's longest-running and most prestigious scholarship and recognition initiative for creative teens National Silver Medal in Design - 2018
 2 Regional Gold Keys, 2 Regional Silver Keys, Honorable Mention
- 28th Annual Upstate High School Art Exhibit
 1st Place Graphic Design, 2018
- All American High School Film Festival Official 2018 Selection
 Short Film Experimental Kinetic Typography

Check out my portfolio -

mikaylazwerdling.com